const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:56,question:"When a salt loses its water of crystallization to the atmosphere on exposure, the process is said to be",option:{a:"Deliquescence",b:"Effervescence",c:"Efflorescence",d:"Fluorescence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:146,question:"The mass of silver deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of silver salt for 4830s is    [Ag = 108, F = 96500 Cmol-1]",option:{a:"108.0g",b:"54.0g",c:"27.0g",d:"13.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:249,question:"One heating may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Cu(NO3)2",b:"AgNO3",c:"Ca(NO3)2",d:"NaNO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:135,question:"Hardness of water is caused by the presence of the ions of",option:{a:"Magnesium and silver",b:"Calcium and magnesium",c:"Sodium and potassium",d:"Calcium and sodium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:238,question:"An example of aliphatic unsaturated hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"Butanol",b:"Propene",c:"Pentane",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:255,question:"In the industrial production of H2 from natural gas, the CO2 produced along with the H2 is removed by",option:{a:"Passing the mixture into lime water",b:"Washing under pressure",c:"Drying over phosphorous(V)oxide",d:"Using ammoniac copper(l) chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:236,question:"If 30cm3 of a gas at 500C is warmed to 800C at a fixed pressure. The fractional increase in volume is",option:{a:"0.91",b:"0.009",c:"1.09",d:"0.093"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:271,question:"Permanent hardness of water can be removed by",option:{a:"Adding slaked lime",b:"Adding caustic soda",c:"Boiling",d:"Filtration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:72,question:"The intermediate product formed when ethanol is progressively oxidized to ethanoic acid with potassium heptaoxodichromate(VI) is",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Methanol",c:"Butanal",d:"Propanal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:31,question:"The general formula for the alkanals is",option:{a:"ROH",b:"R2CO",c:"RCOOR1",d:"RCHO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:234,question:"A degree in atomic size and an increase in knuckler charge across a period lead to",option:{a:"A decrease in covalency in bond formation",b:"An increase in chemical reactivity",c:"An increase in the tendency to loss electrons",d:"A decrease in electro positivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:77,question:"What is the percentage by mass of oxygen in Al2(SO4)3.2H2O",option:{a:"14.29%",b:"25.39%",c:"50.79%",d:"59.25%"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:204,question:"The air around smelting industries is likely to contain",option:{a:"CO2, SO3 and H2",b:"SO2N2 and CO2",c:"H2, SO2 and CO2",d:"H2S, CO and N2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:148,question:"Which of the following hydrogen halides has the highest entropy value",option:{a:"HF",b:"HCl",c:"HBr",d:"Hl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:197,question:"A substance that is used as a ripening agent for fruits is",option:{a:"Propene",b:"Methane",c:"Ethene",d:"Butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:107,question:"Which of the following statements is true of sulphur (IV) oxide",option:{a:"It forms Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid with water",b:"It is an odourless gas",c:"It is an acid anhydride",d:"It forms white precipitate with acidified barium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:69,question:"Hydrogen is readily released when dilute hydrochloric acid reacts with",option:{a:"Au",b:"Cu",c:"Na",d:"Ag"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:67,question:"Ordinary glass is manufactured from silica, Ca CO3 and",option:{a:"K2CO3",b:"NaHCO3",c:"Na2CO3",d:"K2SO4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:62,question:"The processes which return carbon(IV) oxide to the atmosphere include",option:{a:"Photosynthesis, decay and respiration",b:"Photosynthesis, respiration and transpiration",c:"Respiration, decay and combustion",d:"Ozone, depletion, combustion and decay"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:268,question:"The maximum number of electrons in the L shell of an atom is",option:{a:"8",b:"18",c:"32",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:166,question:"The reaction above is",option:{a:"Carboxylation",b:"Decarboxylation",c:"Acidification",d:"Esterification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:221,question:"Forms a layer of oxide on the metal   If the heat of combustion of hydrogen is -285.8kJ. what is the heat of formation of water",option:{a:"-285.8Kj",b:"-571.6kJ",c:"+571kJ",d:"+285.8kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:213,question:"Which of the following equimolar solutions will have the highest pH",option:{a:"NH4OH",b:"CH3COONa",c:"HCI",d:"NaOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:269,question:"Elements in the same periodic table have the same",option:{a:"Atomic number",b:"Chemical properties",c:"Physical properties",d:"Number of shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:299,question:"The final products of the reaction between methane and chloride in the presence of ultraviolet light are hydrogen chloride and",option:{a:"Dichloromethane",b:"Tetrachloromethane",c:"Chloromethane",d:"Trichloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:2,question:"What mass of water is produced when 8.0g of hydriogen reacts with excess oxygen [H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"36.0g",b:"8.0g",c:"72.0g",d:"16.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:61,question:"If 0.75 mole of cyclopropane and 0.66 mole of oxygen are mixed in a vessel with a total pressure of 0.7 atmosphere. What is the partial pressure of oxygen in the mixture",option:{a:"0.55 atmosphere",b:"0.44 atmosphere",c:"0.33 atmosphere",d:"0.22 atmosphere"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:93,question:"When 10g of sodium hydroxide is dissolved in 1000cm3 of water, the solution formed is approximately   [Na = 23, H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.01 mol dm-3",b:"0.10 mol dm-3",c:"0.25 mol dm-3",d:"0.50 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:177,question:"The ores that can be concentrated by flotation are",option:{a:"Nitride ores",b:"Chloride ores",c:"Oxide ores",d:"Sulphide ores"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:124,question:"A chemical reaction is always associated with",option:{a:"An increase in the composition of one of the substances",b:"A change in the volume of the reactants",c:"A change in the nature of the reactants",d:"The formation of new substances"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:262,question:"Calculate the percentage by mass of nitrogen in calcium trioxonitrate (V)   {Ca = 40, N = 14, O = 16}",option:{a:"13.10%",b:"17.10%",c:"27.60%",d:"8.5"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:192,question:"Sugar is separated from its impurities by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Evaporation",c:"Precipitation",d:"Crystallization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:25,question:"3CU(s)  +  8HNO3(aq) →  3Cu(NO3)2(aq)  +  4H2O(I)  +  2NO(g)  In the equation above, copper is",option:{a:"An electron acceptor",b:"A base",c:"An oxidizing agent",d:"A reducing agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:174,question:"To obtain pure carbon(II) oxide from its mixture with carbon (IV)oxide, the mixture should be",option:{a:"Bubbled through concentrated Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid",b:"Bubbled through sodium hydroxide",c:"Passed over heated copper(II) oxide",d:"Bubbled through water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:104,question:"Chlorine gas is prepared in the laboratory by",option:{a:"Adding concentrated hydrochloric acid to solid manganese (IV) oxide",b:"Adding concentrated tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid to solid sodium chloride",c:"Dropping concentrated hydrochloric acid onto potassium tetraoxomanganate (VII) crystals",d:"Oxidizing concentrated hydrochloric acid using potassium heptaoxodichromate (VI) crystals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:9,question:"Which of the following statements is correct about the average kinetic energy of the molecules of a gas",option:{a:"It inctreasaes with increase in pressure",b:"It increases at constant pressure",c:"It increases with increase in temperature",d:"It increases in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:76,question:"Which of the following is a physical change",option:{a:"Burning kerosene",b:"Freezing ice-cream",c:"Exposing white phosphorus to air",d:"Dissolving calcium in water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:88,question:"Which of the following ions is acidic",option:{a:"K+",b:"NO-3",c:"S2-",d:"H3O+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:16,question:"Phosphorous is stored under water to precvent it from",option:{a:"Dehydrating",b:"Becoming inert",c:"Smelling",d:"Catching fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:232,question:"The element with the electron configuration 1s22s22p3 is",option:{a:"Oxygen",b:"Chlorine",c:"Nitrogen",d:"Calcium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:208,question:"A concentrated solution containing H+, Cu2+, OH- and Cl- was electrolyzed using platinum electrodes. The ion that will be discharged at the cathode is",option:{a:"OH-",b:"Cl-",c:"Cu2+",d:"H+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:247,question:"Water has the ability to dissolve almost all substances because its molecule has a structure with",option:{a:"One positive end and one neutral end",b:"Two positive ends",c:"One positive end and one negative end",d:"Two negative ends"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:38,question:"A characteristic reaction of the compounds with the general formula CnH2n is",option:{a:"Esterification",b:"Polymerization",c:"Decarboxylation",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:110,question:"Chlorine gas turns a damp starch-iodide paper",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Colourless",c:"Red",d:"Dark blue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:47,question:"The formula CH2O for ethanoic acid is regarded as its",option:{a:"General formula",b:"Structural formula",c:"Molecular formula",d:"Empirical formula"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:228,question:"The volume of 2.5 moles of oxygen at s.t.p is",option:{a:"56.0dm3",b:"84.0dm3",c:"50.0dm3",d:"20.0dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:80,question:"Neutral atoms of neon with atomic number 10 have the same number of electrons as",option:{a:"O2+",b:"Ca2+",c:"K+",d:"Mg2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:30,question:"Fermentation is the",option:{a:"Breaking down of carbohydrate to glucose",b:"Conversion of sugar to alcohol in the presence of yeast",c:"Breaking down of sugar to carbohydrate",d:"Conversion of alcohol to sugar in the presence of yeast"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:285,question:"If a reaction is exothermic and thee is a great disorder, it means that",option:{a:"The reaction is in a state of equilibrium",b:"There will be a large increase in free energy",c:"There will be a large decrease in free energy",d:"The reaction is static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:127,question:"According to Charles  law, the volume of a gas becomes zero at",option:{a:"00C",b:"-1000C",c:"-2730C",d:"-3730C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:284,question:"In which of the following is the entropy change positive",option:{a:"Reaction between an acid and a base",b:"Addition of concentrated acid to water",c:"Dissolution of sodium metal in water",d:"Thermal dissociation of ammonium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:87,question:"A consequence of global warming is",option:{a:"Air pollution",b:"Water pollution",c:"Increased humidity",d:"Flooding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:293,question:"Stainless steel is used for making",option:{a:"Tools",b:"Coins and medals",c:"Moving parts of clocks",d:"Magnets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:81,question:"The noble gases owe their inactivity to",option:{a:"Octet configuration",b:"Cyclic shape",c:"Hexagonal shape",d:"Obtuse configuration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:79,question:"3Cu  +  pHNO3  → 3Cu(NO3)2  +  4H2O  + xNO   In the equation above, the values of p and x respectively are",option:{a:"1 and 3",b:"2 and 3",c:"6 and 2",d:"8 and 2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:209,question:"Phenolphthalein in acidic solution is",option:{a:"Colourless",b:"Yellow",c:"Red",d:"Orange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:199,question:"The enzyme responsible for converting sucrose into two simple isomeric sugars is",option:{a:"Invertase",b:"Amylase",c:"Lactose",d:"Maltase"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:292,question:"A compound gives an orange red colour to a non luminous flame. This compound is likely to contain",option:{a:"Ca2+",b:"Fe3+",c:"Fe2+",d:"Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:302,question:"The haloalkanes used in the dry cleaning industries are",option:{a:"Chloroethane and dichloroethene",b:"trichloroethene and tetrachloroethene",c:"chloromethane and dichloroethene",d:"Trichloromethane and tetrachloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:106,question:"Hydrogen can be displaced form a hot alkaline solution by",option:{a:"Fe",b:"Cu",c:"Ca",d:"Sn"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:270,question:"A noble gas with a high power of fog penetration used in aerodrome beacons is",option:{a:"Argon",b:"Helium",c:"Neon",d:"Krypton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:123,question:"When a solid substance disappears completely as a gas on heating, the substance is said to have under gone",option:{a:"Evaporation",b:"Distillation",c:"Crystallization",d:"Sublimation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:252,question:"Carbon exists naturally in the combined state as",option:{a:"Diamond",b:"Coal",c:"Wood",d:"Graphite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:304,question:"The compound that is used as an anaesthetic is",option:{a:"CHCI3",b:"CH2C2",c:"CH3CI",d:"CCI4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:198,question:"Which of the following are structural isomers",option:{a:"Propanoic acid and propan-1, 2-diol",b:"Ethanoic acid and propanoic acid",c:"Ethan-1, 2 –diol and ethanoic acid",d:"Propanal and propanone"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:15,question:"The chemiocal used for coagulation in water purification is",option:{a:"Aluminum tetraoxosulphate(VI)",b:"Copper tetratoxosulphate (VI)",c:"Sodium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",d:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate (VI)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:45,question:"Which of the following gases contains the least number of atoms at s.t.p",option:{a:"4 moles of chlorine",b:"3 moles of ozone",c:"1 mole of butane",d:"7 moles of argon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:101,question:` CO(g) + H2O(g) ⇌  CO2(g)  +  H2(g)
From the reaction above, calculate the standard heat change if the standard enthalpies of formation of CO2 (g), H2O (g) and CO (g) in kJ mol-1 are -394, -242 and -110 respectively.
`,option:{a:"-262 kJ  mol-1",b:"-42kJ mol-1",c:"+42 kJ mol-1",d:"+262 kJ mol-1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:261,question:"Which of the following is an example of a mixture",option:{a:"Blood",b:"Sand",c:"Washing soda",d:"Common salt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:181,question:"The most abundant element on the earth’s crust is",option:{a:"Oxygen",b:"Fluorine",c:"hydrogen",d:"nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:137,question:"A carcinogenic substance is",option:{a:"Asbestos dust",b:"Sawdust",c:"Nitrogen(II) oxide",d:"Carbon (II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:272,question:"Substances employed as drying agents are usually",option:{a:"Hygroscopic",b:"Efflorescent",c:"Acidic",d:"Amphoteric"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:264,question:"The volume of a gas is Vcm3 at P mm Hg. What is the new volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to half at constant temperature",option:{a:"2 V cm3",b:"V  2cm3",c:"V cm3",d:"4 V cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:224,question:"5SO2(g)  +  2KMnO4(aq)  +  2H2O(l)  ⇌   K2SO4(aq)  +  2MnSO4(aq)  +   2H2HSO4(aq)   In the reaction above, the products give a",option:{a:"Colourless solution",b:"Purple precipitate",c:"Purple solution",d:"Colourless precipitate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:29,question:"NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)  → NH4CI(s) The entropy change in the system is",option:{a:"Negative",b:"Indeterminate",c:"Positive",d:"Zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:277,question:"Calculate the volume of 0.5 mol dm-3 H2SO4 that is neutralized by 25cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH",option:{a:"2.5cm3",b:"0.4cm3",c:"0.1cm3",d:"5.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:158,question:"Transition metals posses variable oxidation states because they have",option:{a:"Electrons in the d orbitals",b:"Electrons in the s orbitals",c:"A variable number of electrons in the p orbitals",d:"Partially filled p orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:265,question:"Moving from left to right across a period, the general rise in the first ionization energy can be attributed to the",option:{a:"Increase in nuclear charge",b:"Decrease in screening effect",c:"Increase in screening effect",d:"Decrease in nuclear charge"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:133,question:"Chlorine consisting of two isotopes of mass numbers 35 and 37 in the ratio 3:1 has an atomic mass of 35.5. Calculate the relative abundance of the isotope of mass number 37.",option:{a:"20",b:"25",c:"60",d:"75"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:201,question:"Kerosene is commonly used to remove the red colour stain of palm oil from clothes because it",option:{a:"Helps to spread the oil over a larger surface area",b:"Makes the oil evaporate easily by dissolving it",c:"Helps to dilute the oil and reduce its colour",d:"Reacts with the oil to form an odourless compound"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:294,question:"The residual solids from the fractional distillation of petroleum are used as",option:{a:"Raw materials for the cracking process",b:"Fuel for driving tractors",c:"Fuel for jet engines",d:"Coatings for pipes"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:141,question:"What volume of 0.5mol dm-3 H2SO4 will exactly neutralize 20cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH solution",option:{a:"2.0cm3",b:"5.0cm3",c:"6.8cm3",d:"8.3cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:109,question:"The metal that liberates hydrogen from cold water in bubbles only is",option:{a:"Na",b:"K",c:"Ca",d:"Al"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:103,question:"Which of the following is an electrolyte",option:{a:"Alcohol",b:"Sodium acetate solution",c:"Solid potassium hydroxide",d:"Mercury"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:217,question:"Na2CO3(aq)  +  2HCI(aq)  → 2NaCI(aq)  +  H2O(l)  +  CO2(g)    How many moles of sodium trioxocarbonate (IV) are there in a 25cm3 solution which required 10cm3 of 0.05 mol dm-3 hydrochloric acid solution to neutralize it?",option:{a:"0.100mloe",b:"0.001mole",c:"1.000mole",d:"0.010mole"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:157,question:"Alloys are best prepared by",option:{a:"Electroplating",b:"Arc-welding",c:"Reducing a mixture of their metallic oxides",d:"Cooling a molten mixture of the metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:59,question:"25cm3 of a 0.2mol dm-3 solution of Na2CO3 requires 20cm3 of  solution of HCl for neutralization. The concentration of the solution is",option:{a:"0.6 mol dm-3",b:"0.5 mol dm-3",c:"0.4 mol dm-3",d:"0.2 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:44,question:"When sodium reacts with water, the resulting solution is",option:{a:"weakly acdic",b:"neutral",c:"acidic",d:"alkaline"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:291,question:"When iron is exposed to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Anahydrous  iron (III) oxide",b:"Anhydrous iron (II) oxide",c:"Hydrated iron (II) oxide",d:"Hydrated iron  (III) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:91,question:"What mass of K2CrO4 is required to prepare 250cm3 of 0.020 mol dm-3 solution   [K2CrO4 = 194.2g mol-1]",option:{a:"0.97g",b:"9.70g",c:"19.42g",d:"97.10g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:230,question:"2C2H2(g)  +  5O2(g)     4CO2(g)  +  2H2O(g) In the reaction, the mass of carbon (IV) oxide produced on burning 78g of ethyne is [C = 12, O = 16, H = 1]",option:{a:"39",b:"352g",c:"264g",d:"156g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:202,question:"25cm3 of a mixture of noble gases was obtained from air after the removal of other constituents. What was the original volume of air",option:{a:"125cm3",b:"1250cm3",c:"2500cm3",d:"80cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:8,question:"An element X with relative atomic mass 16.2 contains two isotopes      X  with relative abundance of 90% and      X with relative abundance of 10%. The value of m is",option:{a:"16",b:"18",c:"12",d:"14"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:218,question:"The ion that can be used as an oxidizing agent is",option:{a:"Fe3+",b:"F-",c:"Ca2+",d:"Au3+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:286,question:"In the preparation of oxygen by heating KCIO3 in the presence of MnC2, only moderate hear is needed because the catalyst acts by",option:{a:"Increasing the surface area of the reactant",b:"Increasing the rate of the reaction",c:"Lowering the energy barrier of the reaction",d:"Lowering the pressure of the reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:90,question:"A liquid that will dissolve fast is",option:{a:"Hydrochloric acid",b:"Calcium hydroxide",c:"Kerosene",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
